《美国狂人》
今晚的面点
Our pasta this evening is squid ravioIi in a Iemon grass broth...
是柠檬香草汤鱿鱼小方饺
还有羊乳甜饼和芝麻菜凯萨色拉
...with goat cheese profiteroIes. And I aIso have an aruguIa Caesar saIad.
今晚的主菜是箭鱼肉糜糕和洋葱果酱
For entrees, I have swordfish meatIoaf with onion marmaIade.
黑莓汁半熟烤鹌鹑脯和酸模夹心烤馅饼
Rare roasted partridge breast in raspberry couIis with a sorreI timbaIe.
还有烧烤野兔肉，炸薯条做底
And griIIed free range rabbit with herb french fries.
今晚的面点是柠檬香草汤鱿鱼小方饺
Our pasta tonight is a squid ravioIi in a Iemon grass broth....
-天哪，我讨厌这地方 这是小娘们的餐馆 -干吗不去Dorsia？
God, I hate this pIace. It's a chick's restaurant.
因为Bateman和那儿的领班闹别扭
Why not Dorsia?
Because Bateman won't give the maitre d' head.
那边的是Reed Robinson吗？
Is that Reed Robinson?
-你是不是药嗑多了？那才不是Robinson呢 -那么是谁？
-You freebasing? That's not Robinson. -Who is it then?
-是Paul Allen -不是吧
-That's PauI AIIen. -That's not PauI AIIen.
Paul Allen在屋子的另外一头
-PauI AIIen's on the other side of the room. -Who's he with?
-他和谁在一起？ -从Kikcer Peabody来的蠢货
Some weaseI from Kicker Peabody.
这儿连嗑药的好点的洗手间都没有
Can't do coke in this bathroom.
-你肯定那边的是Paul Allen吗？ -没错,Mc Dufus，我肯定
-Are you sure that's PauI AIIen? -Yes, McDufus.
-他在做Fisher那单生意 -走运的家伙
He handIes the Fisher account.
-走运的犹太家伙 -上帝啊，Mc Dermott，那有任何关系吗？
-Lucky bastard. -Lucky Jew bastard.
What does that have to do with anything?
我看到那家伙在他办公室里
I've seen that bastard in his office on the phone with CEO's...
一面和CEO通电话，一面玩在转他妈的烛台
-...spinning a fucking menorah. -Not a menorah. You spin a dreideI.
不是烛台，他们转的是陀螺
哦，天哪，Bateman
Oh, my God, do you want me to fry you up some fucking potato pancakes?
你想让我给你炸点马铃薯薄饼吗？土豆饼？
不，只是…少说两句反犹太的话吧
-Some Iatkes? -No. Just...
...cooI it with the anti-Semitic remarks.
哦，我忘了 Bateman在和美国公民自由协会的人约会呢
I forgot. Bateman's dating someone from the ACLU.
他是理智的代言人，一个隔壁男孩
The voice of reason. The boy next door.
谈到理智-- 只要570块
Speaking of reasonabIe...
还不错嘛
...onIy $570.
Not bad.
稍微掏了点腰包
给她50块小费
" l used to think that the day would never come "
" l'd see the light the shade of the morning sun "
" My morning sun is the drug that brings me here "
" To the child lost replaced by fear "
" l used to think that the day would never come "
" That my life would begin to "
来杯“Stoli on the rocks”
Two StoIi on the rocks.
这不能用了 这是付现金的酒吧
These aren't good any more. It's a cash bar.
25块钱
That wiII be $25.
你他们的臭婊子
You're a fucking ugIy bitch.
我要把你捅了
I want to stab you to death and pIay around with your bIood.
再玩你的血
两位要什么？
我住在在西81街
I Iive in the American Gardens BuiIding on West 81st Street...
美国公园大厦十一楼
...on the 1 1th fIoor.
我叫Partick Bateman
My name is Patrick Bateman. I'm 27 years oId.
现年27岁
我信奉自我养生
I beIieve in taking care of myseIf...
定量进餐，大量运动
...in a baIanced diet and a rigorous exercise routine.
每天早晨，如果我的脸皮有点松
In the morning, if my face is a IittIe puffy...
我会在做俯卧撑的时候上上冰袋
...I'II put on an ice pack whiIe doing my stomach crunches.
我现在能做一千下了
I can do 1,000 now.
除下冰袋后，我要用深层毛孔清洁露
After I remove the ice pack, I use a deep pore cIeanser Iotion.
在冲澡的时候，我会上一种水洗凝胶清洁剂
In the shower, I use a water-activated geI cIeanser...
然后是蜜炼杏仁磨砂沐浴露
...then, a honey-aImond body scrub...
再在脸上用去角质磨砂胶
...and on the face, an exfoIiating geI scrub.
接着我会做个薄荷草药面膜
Then, I appIy a herb mint faciaI mask...
在等待的10分钟里 我会为其他的日常程序做准备工作
...which I Ieave on for 10 minutes, whiIe I prepare the rest of my routine.
我总上用不含或只含少量酒精的刮面后香露
I aIways use an aftershave Iotion with IittIe or no aIcohoI...
因为酒精会让你的面部干燥，看起来更老
...because aIcohoI dries your face out and makes you Iook oIder...
然后是润肤露
...then, moisturiser...
然后是抗衰老眼霜
...then, an anti-ageing eye baIm...
最后是润润护肤露
...foIIowed by a finaI moisturising protective Iotion.
Patrick Bateman是一个意象
There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman...
很抽象，但并非真正的我
...some kind of abstraction, but there is no reaI me...
只是那么一个意象-- 非常模糊
...onIy an entity, something iIIusory.
并且尽管我可以掩藏冷酷
And though I can hide my coId gaze...
你与我握手仍感觉到我有血有肉
...and you can shake my hand and feeI fIesh gripping yours...
而且你甚至会感到 我们的生活方式颇为相似
...and maybe you can even sense our IifestyIes are probabIy comparabIe...
但我其实并非真我
...I simpIy am not there.
" Ow "
" Mmm,yeah "
" l said,baby l just want you back "
" And l want you to stay "
" Whoa " Good morning.
" l'm walking on sunshine " Good morning,Hamilton. Nice tan.
" Whoa l'm walking on sunshine "
Morning, HamiIton. Nice tan.
" Whoa "
来晚了 有氧操班有课，对不起 有人找吗？
-Late? -Aerobics cIass. Sorry. Any messages?
Risky Harrison的约会取消了 他没说他取消的是什么约会及其原因
Ricky Harrison canceIIed. He didn't say what he was canceIIing or why.
我有时候会约Ricky在哈佛俱乐部打拳 还有呢？
I occasionaIIy box with Ricky at the Harvard CIub. Anyone eIse?
-Spencer约你在17号码头的Fluties喝酒 -什么时候？
Spencer wants to meet for drinks at FIuties Pier 1 7.
-6点以后 我该怎么答复？ -不行，推掉
-When? -After 6:00.
Negative. CanceI it.
-就说“不行” -就说“不行”？
-And what shouId I say? -Just say no.
Just say no?
好了，Jean
Okay, Jean.
帮我在Camols订三个位，12点半
I need reservations for three at CamoIs...
如果订不到就换Crayons
...at 12:30 and if not, try Crayons.
-好吗？ -好的
-AII right? -Yes sir.
哦，等等 我还要在Arcadia 订两个位，星期四8点
Wait. And I need reservations for two...
...at Arcadia at 8:00 on Thursday.
浪漫晚餐？
Something romantic?
不是
No.
挺傻的 当我没说过 我自己来吧
SiIIy.
-不，我来订 -不，不
-Forget it. I'II make them. -No, I'II do it.
-听话，给我拿杯矿泉水来，好吗？ -你今天气色不错
No. Be a doII and just get me a mineraI water, okay?
别再穿这套衣服了
-You Iook nice today. -Don't wear that outfit again.
什么？我没听清
What? I didn't hear you.
我说，你别再穿这套衣服了
I said, ''Do not wear that outfit again.''
-穿套装，裙子或者别的什么 -你不喜欢，但我穿的很衬
Wear a dress. A skirt or something.
得了，你打扮起来会更靓的
-You don't Iike this, I take it? -Come on...
...you're prettier than that.
-谢了，Patrick -说我不在
Thanks, Patrick.
还有高跟鞋，我喜欢高跟的
I'm not here. And high heeIs.
I Iike high heeIs.
" She's a craze you'd endorse She's a powerful force "
" You're obliged to conform when there's no other course "
" She used to look good to me but now l find her "
" Simply irresistible " 我还要成百上千朵玫瑰
Hundreds, thousands of roses.
还有很多很多的巧克力糖
And Iots of chocoIate truffIes. Godiva. And oysters on the haIf sheII.
在Godiva，再加上分半打开的牡蛎
我想好好听听Robert Palmer新出的带子
I'm Iistening to the new Robert PaImer tape...
可Evelyn，我所谓的未婚妻 在我耳边唠叨个不停
...but EveIyn, my supposed fianc鑕, keeps buzzing in my ear.
Annie Leibovitz 我们要把Annie Leibovitz请来
Photographers.
Annie Leibovitz. We'II get Annie Leibovitz.
我们还得请个摄像师
And we'II have to get someone to videotape it.
" lt's simply unavoidable " Patrick，我们必须这么做
Patrick, we shouId do it.
-做什么？ -结婚，举行婚宴
Do what?
不行，我工作太忙没时间
-Get married. -No. I can't take the time off work.
你老爸差不多控制了整个公司 你想干啥就能干啥，傻瓜
Your father owns the company. You can do anything, siIIy.
-我不想谈这事 -我反正也不喜欢这份差事
-I don't want to taIk about it. -You hate that job anyway.
我不明白你干吗还在那儿干
I don't see why you just don't quit.
因为我想和他们打成一片
Because I want to fit in.
" Simply irresistible "
Williams派对
WiIIiams' party.
我们到Espace的时候我都快哭了
I'm on the verge of tears by the time we arrive at Espace...
因为我几乎肯定我们定不到好位子了
...since I'm positive we won't have a decent tabIe.
可是我们居然订到了 这让我长出了一口气
But we do.
And reIief washes over me in an awesome wave.
Patrick，这是我侄女Vanden和她男朋友Stash
This is my cousin, Vanden, and her boyfriend, Stash.
-他们都是搞艺术的 -菜单是用盲文写的
-They're both artists. -The menu is in braiIIe.
-我想你每个人都见过了 -你美极了
好的，好了
我差不多可以确定
I'm fairIy certain that Timothy Bryce and EveIyn are having an affair.
Timothy Bryce和Evelyn有私情
Timothy是我认识的人里面唯一一个有趣的人物
Timothy is the onIy interesting person I know.
我也根本不在乎Evelyn知不知道
I'm aImost compIeteIy indifferent as to whether EveIyn knows...
我和她最好的朋友Coutney Rawlinson也有私情
...I'm having an affair with Courtney RawIinson...
...her cIosest friend.
Courteny的相貌近乎完美
Courtney is aImost perfect Iooking.
她通常都在用一或几种迷幻药
She usuaIIy operates on one or more psychiatric drugs.
今晚我想是Xanax 嗯，哦
Tonight, I beIieve it's Xanax.
比她嗑药更烦人的是
More disturbing than her drug use, though...
她和Luis Carruthers，本行最大的蠢材定了婚
...is the fact that she's engaged to Luis Carruthers.
-The biggest dufus in the business. -TeII me, Stash...
告诉我，Stash
你觉得休南区是不是变得太…商业化了？
...do you think Soho is becoming too commerciaI?
-是的，我感觉到了 -哦，谁说的屁话
Yes, I read that.
Who gives a rat's ass?
嘿，那会影响到我们的
That affects us.
好吧，那斯里兰卡的大屠杀呢？ 对我们也有影响吗？
What about the massacres in Sri Lanka, honey?
你对斯里兰卡了解多少？
Doesn't that affect us too? Do you know anything about Sri Lanka?
多少，比如说，锡克教徒在那里 杀了成千上万的以色列人
The Sikhs are kiIIing tons of IsraeIis.
得了，Bryce
Come on, Bryce. There are a Iot more important probIems than Sri Lanka...
比斯里兰卡更严重的问题多得很呢
-比如？ -我们得废除种族隔离制度，这是一桩
-...to worry about. -Like what?
We have to end apartheid for one.
减缓核军备竞赛，终结恐怖主义和世界饥荒
And sIow down the nucIear arms race.
Stop terrorism and worId hunger.
我们要为无家可归者提供食物和住所
We have to provide food and sheIter for the homeIess.
还有反对种族歧视和提高人权
And oppose raciaI discrimination and promote civiI rights...
同时还要提高妇女平等权利
...whiIe aIso promoting equaI rights for women.
我们要推动传统道德价值
We have to encourage a return...
的回归
...to traditionaI, moraI vaIues.
最重要的
Most importantIy, we have to promote generaI sociaI concern.
我们要提高全面社会责任感
并且让年轻人不再那么唯利是图
And Iess materiaIism in young peopIe.
Patrick，多么鼓舞人心的思想啊
Patrick...
...how thought provoking.
你好
HeIIo.
漂白？你是要说“漂白”吗？
BIeaching? Are you trying to say bIeaching? Oh, my God.
哦，上帝啊 有两件事
Two things. One. You can't bIeach a Cerruti. Out of the question.
第一：切瑞蒂的东西不是想漂白就能漂白的 根本不可能
第二：这床单只能在圣达菲才买得到
Two. I can onIy get these sheets in Santa Fe.
这些床单价值不菲，我一定要把它们洗干净
These are very expensive sheets and I need them cIean.
太太，你要是再不闭上你的臭嘴，我就杀了你
If you don't shut your fucking mouth, I wiII kiII you.
现在，听好
I'm having Iunch at Hubert's in 20 minutes with RonaId Harrison.
我再过20分钟就要和Ronald Harrison 在Hubert饭店开个午餐会了
我希望床单能在今天下午前洗干净
I need those sheets cIeaned this afternoon. Listen, I cannot understand you!
听着，我听不懂你的话！ 真见鬼！你这个笨蛋
我和你这种愚蠢的“娘们儿”没法谈！
This is crazy. You're a fooI. I can't cope with this.
-懂了吗？天哪 -Patrick？
Stupid bIeaching! Understand!
嗨，Patrick
Patrick?
-我猜就是你 -你好，那个--
-Hi, Patrick. I thought that was you. -HeIIo.
不是很可笑吗，大老远跑来？ 这确实是最好的洗衣店了
Isn't it ridicuIous? Coming aII the way up here, but they're the best.
那么他们怎么洗不掉这些污迹？
Then why can't they get the stains out?
我是说，你能和他们谈谈吗？ 我跟他们一点说不通
I mean, can you taIk to these peopIe or something? I'm not getting anywhere.
-哦，这是什么呀？ -唔，这是--
What are those?
-酸果蔓汁 -真的吗？
It's cranberry juice. CranappIe.
听着，如果你能帮我跟他们说说， 我真的很感谢
ReaIIy?
If you couId taIk to them, I'd reaIIy appreciate it. I'm reaIIy Iate.
太晚了，再过15分钟我在Hubert饭店有个约会
-I have to be at Hubert's in 15 minutes. -Hubert's? That moved uptown, right?
-Hubert饭店？不是搬到新市区了吗？ -哦，天哪
听着，我得走了 谢谢你，Victoria
WeII, boy, I've got to go. Thank you, Victoria.
也许下星期哪一天我们一起吃顿午饭
Maybe we couId do Iunch next week?
-我常来市区的，星期六怎么样？ -我成天都在工作，恐怕不行
-I'm downtown at-- -I don't know.
-I'm at work aII the time. -What about a Saturday?
-下周六呢？ -没问题
-Next Saturday? -Sure.
Les Mis女子合唱队日场表演见 听着我真的必须走了
Can't, I've matinee of Les Mis.
-哦，天哪，我会给你打电话的 -好的 干吧
-I've reaIIy got to go. Christ! I'II caII you. -Okay.
听着，你在和Lewis约会，他从亚利桑那州来
Do.
你在耍我，我们根本没有这种安排
You're dating Luis. He's in Arizona. You're fucking me.
你今晚会吃什么药？
We haven't made pIans. What couId you be up to tonight?
-别说了，我-- -吃一大把锂剂？
-Stop it. I'm.... -On a Iot of Iithium?
在等Luis的电话 他说今晚要给我打的
Waiting for Luis to caII me. He said he'd caII tonight.
Pumpkin？Pumpkin，你在和一个混蛋约会
Pumpkin?
Pumpkin，你在和纽约最没用的臭小子约会
You're dating an asshoIe.
Pumpkin, you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.
Pumpkin，你在和一个歪七倒八的臭小子约会
Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbIing, tumbIing dickweed.
Patrick，别再叫我pumpkin了，好吗？
Patrick, stop caIIing me ''Pumpkin, '' okay?
-我得挂了 -Courtney？
I have to go.
-嗯？ -去吃饭
Courtney? Dinner?
-不行 -我说去Dorsia
I can't.
I'm thinking Dorsia.
-Dorisa还不错 -打扮得漂亮点
Dorsia's nice.
Wear something fabuIous.
哦，耶！
Dorsia
-Dorsia. -Yes.
嗯，我知道有点晚了
但还有可能订到两个8点到8点半的位子吗？
I know it's Iate, but is it possibIe to reserve a tabIe for two at 8:00 or 8:30 perhaps?
在Elizabeth Arden做一下脸 真的很舒服
A faciaI at EIizabeth Arden, which was reaIIy reIaxing...
然后去Pottery Barn
...and then to the Pottery Barn...
在那儿我买到了
...where I got this IittIe siIver muffin dish.
-这个小银松饼盒 -那是Donald Trump的车吗？
上帝啊，Partick，别作声
-Is that DonaId Trump's car? -Oh God, Patrick. Shut up.
你知道吗，Courtney， 你应该再吃点锂剂，或者喝杯可乐
You shouId take more Iithium or have a Diet Coke.
咖啡因或许能帮你摆脱现在的疲塌
Some caffeine might get you out of this sIump.
我只想要一个孩子
I just want a chiId.
两个
Just two perfect...
完美无暇的
孩子
...chiIdren.
-我们到了吗？ -是的
-Are we here? -Yeah.
-这儿是Dorsia吗？ -是的，亲爱的
This is Dorsia?
Courtney，你马上就会尝到花生酱汤
Yes, dear.
熏鸭和南瓜泥
You're gonna have the peanut butter soup with smoked duck and mashed squash.
New York Matinee把这个叫 “好玩又神秘的小菜”
New York Matin鑕 caIIed it, ''a pIayfuI but mysterious IittIe dish.''
你会喜欢的 接下来是紫罗兰和松子衬底的红鲷鱼
You'II Iove it.
And then the red snapper with vioIets and pine nuts.
我想这样的搭配很合适
I think that'II foIIow niceIy.
谢谢，Patrick
Thanks, Patrick.
Patrick，多谢你照看Courtney
Patrick, thanks so much for Iooking after Courtney.
Dorsia，真让人难忘
Dorsia, how impressive!
你到底怎么在这儿订到位的？
How on earth did you get a reservation?
运气吧，我想
Lucky, I guess.
这西装棒极了
That's a wonderfuI suit.
别告诉我，别讲，让我猜
Don't teII me, Iet me guess.
唔。是华伦天奴吗？
-嗯哼 -唔
VaIentino Couture?
-看起来料子真软 -君子动口不动手，Luis
It Iooks so soft.
Your compIiment was sufficient, Luis.
你好，Halberstram，好炫的领带 你还好吗？
HeIIo, HaIberstram. Nice tie.
Allen把我误认成那个蠢货Marcus Halberstram了
How the heII are you?
AIIen has mistaken me for this dickhead, Marcus HaIberstram.
因为Marcus也在P&P工作，这倒也合理
It seems IogicaI because Marcus aIso works at P & P...
而且他干的活和我一模一样
...and does the same exact thing I do.
他也爱穿华伦天奴西服， 戴Oliver Peoples眼镜
He aIso has a penchant for VaIentino suits and OIiver PeopIe's gIasses.
Marcus和我去的理发店都是一家
We even go to the same barber, aIthough I have a sIightIy better haircut.
而我的发型比他稍微好那么一点
-Ransom那单生意怎么样了？ -嗯，一切正常
So how's the Ransom account going?
是吗？有趣 你没说好极了
-It's aII right. -ReaIIy? That's interesting. It's not...
-哦，嗯，你知道的 -那么，Cecilia呢？
-...great? -WeII, you know.
-她是个好姑娘 -哦，没错，我很幸运
-So how's CeceIia? She's a great girI. -Yeah.
-嗯 -嘿，Allen，恭喜你在做Fisher那单生意
-I'm very Iucky. -Hey, AIIen!
-谢谢，Baxter -听着，我叫Paul，笨蛋
-CongratuIations on the Fisher account. -Thank you, Baxter.
PauI. Squash?
给我打电话 星期五怎么样？
CaII me.
不行啊，我8点半在Dorsia订了位
-How about Friday? -No can do.
I got an 8:30 res at Dorsia.
美味的海胆酸橘汁腌鱼
Great sea urchin ceviche.
Dorsia星期五的位子？ 他怎么抢到的？
Dorsia on a Friday night? How'd he swing that?
我想他在吹牛
I think he's Iying.
-什么东西？ -新名片
Is that a gram?
你们看怎么样？
New card. What do you think?
哇嚯，棒极了
-瞧瞧 -昨天才印出来的
Very nice.
Look at that.
Picked them up yesterday.
合理配色，这是关键
-Good coIouring. -That's bone.
用了一种叫Silian Rail的字体
And the Iettering is something caIIed SiIian RaiI.
很酷，Bateman，但算不了啥 看这个
It's very cooI, Bateman. But that's nothing.
真是太棒了
-Look at this. -That is reaIIy nice.
淡褐色，Romalian字体 你看怎么样？
EggsheII with RomaIian type.
很好
What do you think?
天哪，真是盖了 你这种傻瓜蛋怎么变得这么有品位了？
Nice.
Jesus. That is reaIIy super.
How'd a nitwit Iike you get so tastefuI?
我不敢相信
I can't beIieve that Bryce prefers Van Patten's card to mine.
Bryce居然认为Van Patten的名片比我的好
但是别急，你们还没看到好的呢
But wait. You ain't seen nothin' yet.
Raised字体，淡色光晕…白底
Raised Iettering, PaIe Nimbus.
White.
令人难忘 太好了
Impressive. Very nice.
嗯
让我们见识一下Paul Allen的名片
Let's see PauI AIIen's card.
看看那精巧的白色配色
Look at that subtIe off-white coIouring.
品位十足的内蕴
The tastefuI thickness of it.
哦，上帝啊 它还带了水印
Oh, my God, it even has a watermark.
有什么不妥吗，Patrick？
Is something wrong? Patrick? You're sweating.
你出了好多汗
你好，我是Pat Bateman
HeIIo. Pat Bateman.
你要…嗯…钱吗？
You want some money?
还有食物？
Some food?
-你要的是这些吗？ -我…我饿坏了
-Is this what you need? -I'm hungry.
是啊，还冻坏了，是不是？
Yeah, it's coId out too, isn't it?
干吗不找份活干？ 你这么饿，干吗不找份活干？
Why don't you get a job?
我失业了
-If you're so hungry, why not get a job? -I Iost my job.
为什么？你酗酒吗？
Why? You're drinking?
你就是为此丢了饭碗的吗？ 还是做了什么内部交易？
Is that why you Iost it?
开玩笑而已
Insider trading?
-听着，你叫什么？ -Al
Just joking.
What's your name?
嗯？说响点，快点 -Al
-AI. -Speak up! Come on.
去找份活干，Al
-AI. -Get a goddamn job, AI.
你消极处事，就是这个拖了你的后腿
You've got a negative attitude.
你必须努力振作，我会帮你的
That's what's stopping you. You've got to get your act together.
你真好，先生 你是个--是个好人
I'II heIp you.
You are so kind, mister. You're kind.
-没什么的 -我看得出来
-You're a kind man. -It's okay.
求求你，你要告诉我该怎么做 你得帮帮我
PIease, you got to teII me what to do. You got to heIp me. I'm so coId.
我冻坏了 也饿极了
I'm hungry.
你知道你有多臭吗？
你象堆臭狗屎，你知道吗？
Do you know how bad you smeII? You reek of shit. Do you know that?
Al
真抱歉，是因为--
I'm sorry.
我也不知道
It's just that....
I don't know.
我和你根本不是一路人
I don't have anything in common with you.
哦，哦，谢谢你，先生，谢谢你
Thank you, mister. Thank you.
我冻怀了
-你知道你是怎么样的一个窝囊废吗？ -什么？
I'm coId out here.
Do you know what a fucking Ioser you are?
你的皮肤真好，Bateman先生
What beautifuI skin you have, Mr. Bateman.
那么细腻，光滑
So fine. So smooth.
我具有人类的一切特征--
I have aII the characteristics of a human being:
发肤血肉
FIesh, bIood, skin, hair.
但没有一个清晰可辨的表情
But not a singIe cIear, identifiabIe emotion...
除了贪婪和厌恶
...except for greed and disgust.
我内心深处发生了可怕的变化
Something horribIe is happening inside of me.
但我不知道为什么
And I don't know why.
我属于黑夜的嗜血恶性蔓延到了白昼
My nightIy bIoodIust has overfIowed into my days.
我感到了垂死的气息 处于狂怒的边缘
I feeI IethaI, on the verge of frenzy.
我想我理智的面具就快跌落了
I think my mask of sanity is about to sIip.
" Deck the halls with boughs of holly "
" Fa la la la la La la la la "
" 'Tis the season to be jolly "
嘿，Mc Cloy，是说什么？
Hey, McCIoy, what do you say?
嘿，Hamilton 圣诞快乐
HamiIton, have a hoIIy joIIy Christmas. Is AIIen stiII handIing the Fisher account?
-Allen还在接收Fisher那单生意吗？ -当然，还能有谁？
-圣诞问候 -圣诞快乐，Patrick
-Of course, who eIse? -MistIetoe aIert!
-圣诞快乐，Harry -圣诞快乐
Merry Xmas, Patrick! Merry Xmas, Harry!
-你来晚了，亲爱的 是的，你晚了 -我没来晚
-Merry Christmas. -You're Iate, honey.
我一直在这儿，你没看到我罢了
-No. -Yes, you are.
I've been here the entire time. You just didn't see me.
跟雪球说声好 雪球说“圣诞快乐，Patrick”
Say heIIo to SnowbaII. SnowbaII says, ''Merry Christmas, Patrick.''
-什么呀？ -一只可爱的小猪猪，不是吗？
-What is it? -It's a IittIe baby piggy-wiggy, isn't it?
是只越南大肚子猪
It's a Vietnamese pot-beIIied pig. They make darIing pets. Don't you?
真是可爱的宠物，不是吗？
不是吗？
别闷闷不乐的，Patrick 你简直就和Grinch一样了
Stop scowIing, Patrick. You're such a Grinch.
那么Grinch先生有何圣诞心愿？
What's Mr. Grinch want for Christmas? And don't say breast impIants again.
别再提隆胸的事了
-Allen -Marcus，圣诞快乐
-AIIen! -Marcus!
-你怎么样？埋头工作吗？ -好久不见了
Merry Christmas! How have you been? WorkahoIic, I suppose.
嘿，Hamilton，我们要去Nell饭店了 车子在前面等着呢
Haven't seen you in a whiIe.
HamiIton, we're going to NeII's. Limo's out front.
-我们应该一起吃顿饭 -也许你能带上--
-We shouId have dinner. -Maybe you couId bring....
-Cecilla？ -对，Cecilla
-CeceIia? -Yes, CeceIia.
哦，Cecilla会求之不得的
CeceIia wouId adore it.
那么好，就这么定了，Marcus
WeII then, Iet's do it, Marcus.
-很好的派对 -谢谢
-Great party. -Thanks.
Patrick，他怎么叫你Marcus呢？
Patrick, why is he caIIing you Marcus?
圣诞问候
MistIetoe aIert!
Marcus Halberstram定的两个7点的位
Marcus HaIberstram for two at 7:00.
不，我想知道，行不行？ 我就是为这里的芫荽龙虾汤来的
No, I want to know....
Okay, I came here for the ciIantro fish gumbo, aII right?
这也是我们来这家餐馆的唯一理由
It's the onIy excuse one couId have for being here, which is...
可是这现在却空空如也
...by the way, aImost compIeteIy empty.
-非常抱歉，先生 -J&B不掺水，再来杯Corona啤酒
-I'm very sorry, sir. -J & B straight and a Corona.
-要听听-- -双份纯马提尼酒
-WouId you Iike to-- -DoubIe AbsoIut martini!
好的，先生 要听听今晚的特色菜吗？
Yes, sir.
不想惹火的话就免了吧
-WouId you Iike to hear the speciaIs? -Not if you want to keep your spIeen.
人们蜂拥而至，这里真够热闹的
This is a reaI beehive of activity, HaIberstram.
-非常热闹 -听着，这里的混汤和炭烧芝麻菜
This pIace is hot, very hot.
The mud soup and the charcoaI aruguIa are outrageous here.
真实非同凡响
-是吗，好吧，你来晚了 -嘿，我身不由己
Yeah, weII, you're Iate.
饶了我吧
I'm a chiId of divorce. Give me a break.
-我想他们把猪里脊换成果子冻了 -我们应该去Dorsia的
I see they've omitted the pork Ioin with Iime jeIIo.
We shouId've gone to Dorsia.
我应该在那儿订个位的 -没人再去那儿了
-I couId've gotten us a tabIe. -Nobody goes there anymore.
那是Ivana Trump吗？
Is that Ivana Trump?
哦，天，Patrick 我是说，Marcus，你在想什么？
Jeez, Patrick. I mean Marcus. What are you thinking?
Ivana怎么会在Texarkana出现？
Why wouId Ivana be at Texarkana?
那么，嗯，原来不是Rothchild在做Fisher那单生意吗？
So, wasn't RothschiId originaIIy handIing the Fisher account?
-你怎么弄到收的？ -这我可以告诉你，Halberstram
How'd you get it?
I couId teII you that, HaIberstram...
但随后我就要杀你灭口
...but then I'd have to kiII you.
我喜欢肢解少女 你不知道我已经极度疯狂了吗？
I Iike to dissect girIs. Did you know I'm utterIy insane?
你肤色真不错，我是说非常引人注目
Great tan, Marcus. ReaIIy impressive.
-在哪儿晒的？ -沙龙里
-Where do you tan? -SaIon.
我家里有张晒床，你应该过来看看
I've got a tanning bed at home. You shouId Iook into it.
还有，嗯，Cecilla
And CeceIia? How is she?
她怎么样了？他今晚在哪儿？
Cecilla在，嗯-- 你也知道她这个人啦
-Where is she tonight? -WeII, you know CeceIia....
我想她在和，嗯，Evelyn Williams共进晚餐呢
I think she's having dinner with EveIyn WiIIiams.
Evelyn？超级美臀
EveIyn?
和那个窝囊废Patrick Bateman 混在一起，真可惜
Great ass. Goes out with that Ioser, Patrick Bateman. What a dork!
再来杯马提尼，Paul？
Another martini, PauI?
你喜欢Huey Lewis & the News的歌吗？
You Iike Huey Lewis & the News?
嗯，还好啦
They're okay.
他们的早期作品对我而言太前卫了些
Their earIy work was a IittIe too New Wave for my taste.
但83年Sports专集出来的时候
But when Sports came out in '83...
我想他们真正找到了自我，无论在市场上还是艺术上
...I think they reaIIy came into their own, commerciaIIy and artisticaIIy.
整张专集声音明朗干脆
The whoIe aIbum has a cIear, crisp sound...
趋于完美的专业演绎焕发出的崭新光辉
...and a new sheen of consummate professionaIism...
着实为这些单曲增色不少
...that reaIIy gives the songs a big boost.
他已经和Elvis Costello相提并论
He's been compared to EIvis CosteIIo.
但我以为Huey具有更为良好的 愤世嫉俗的的幽默感
But I think Huey has a far more bitter, cynicaI sense of humour.
-喂，Halberstram？ -什么事，Allen？
-Hey, HaIberstram? -Yes, AIIen?
为什么到处都是流行服饰的专栏？
Why are there copies of the StyIe section aII over the pIace?
你有--你有养狗吗？ 有狗粮之类的东西吗？
Do you have a dog? A IittIe chow or something?
-没有，Allen -那是雨衣吗？
No, AIIen.
是的，没错
-Is that a raincoat? -Yes, it is.
87年Huey推出了
In 1987, Huey reIeased this, Four, their most accompIished aIbum.
Force，他的最佳专集
我认为最佳单曲毫无疑问应归于Hip to Be Square
I think their undisputed masterpiece is Hip To Be Square.
这首歌如此吸引人， 以至大多数人可能都不会去听歌词
A song so catchy that most peopIe probabIy don't Iisten to the Iyrics.
但歌词是值得回味的 因为它不光是说
But they shouId because it's not just about the pIeasures of conformity...
迎合时尚之快乐 以及流行潮流之重要
它也是乐队的个人宣言 嘿，Paul！
...and the importance of trends. It's aIso a personaI statement about the band itseIf.
Hey, PauI!
" You couldn't take the punishment "
" And had to settle down " 现在去Dorsia定位呀
Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now, you fucking stupid bastard!
你这个蠢货！ " Now,l'm playing it real straight "
他妈的混蛋！ " And yes,l cut my hair "
" You might think l'm crazy but l don't even care "
" 'Cause l can tell what's going on "
" lt's hip to be square "
" like my bands in mini-suits "
" l watch them on TV "
" l'm working out most everyday "
" And watching what l eat "
" They tell me that it's good for me "
" But l don't even care "
" l know that it's crazy l know that it's nowhere "
" But there is no denying that "
" lt's hip to be square "
他全身赤裸站在桌子上
什么都没穿，并且--
Patrick？ Patrick
Patrick? Patrick?
是你吗？
不，Luis，不是我 你搞错了
-Is that you? -No, Luis. It's not me.
这是我最好的朋友，Patrick Bateman
You're mistaken.
This is my very good friend, Patrick Bateman.
你去哪儿？我们要去Nell餐馆 Gwendolyn的父亲要把它买下来
Where are you going? We're going to NeII's.
噢
GwendoIyn's father is buying it.
你从哪儿搞来的这睡袋？
Where did you get that overnight bag?
在Jean-Paul Gaultier买的
Jean PauI GauItier.
我到了Paul Allen的家
When I get to PauI AIIen's pIace, I use the keys I took from his pocket...
用他口袋的的钥匙开的门
在处置尸体之前
...before disposing of the body.
我着实惊慌了一阵
There is a moment of sheer panic...
当我看到Paul的公寓对面就是公园
...when I reaIise that PauI's apartment overIooks the park.
显然房价要比我的高得多
And is obviousIy more expensive than mine.
我让自己平静下来，进入他的卧室
I caIm myseIf, and move into the bedroom...
找到了他的皮箱并开始装行李
...where I find his suitcase and start to pack.
Paul该去做个短途旅行了
It's time for PauI to take a IittIe trip.
我该把这混蛋送到哪儿去呢？
Where to send the bastard?
达拉斯？
DaIIas?
巴黎？新加坡？
Paris? Singapore? London? I'II send the asshoIe to London.
伦敦？我要把这混蛋送到伦敦去
嗨，我是Paul
我被派到伦敦出几天差
Hi, this is PauI. I've been caIIed to London for a few days.
Meredith，我回来就给你打电话 回头见，宝贝
Meredith, I'II caII you when I get back. Hasta Ia vista, baby.
" Lady in red "
" ls dancing with me "
" Cheek to cheek "
" There's nobody here "
什么事？
What is it?
-Patrick -什么，Jean？
Patrick, it's just....
-有位Donal Kimball先生要见你 -谁？
Yes, Jean?
-Mr. DonaId KimbaII is here to see you. -Who?
Donald Kimball探长
Detective DonaId KimbaII?
告诉他我去吃午餐了
Patrick，现在才10点半 我想他知道你在这儿
TeII him I'm at Iunch.
Patrick, it's onIy 10:30. I think he knows you're here.
那么就让他进来吧
Send him in, I guess.
听着，John，你该穿合你体型的衣服
Now John, you've got to wear cIothes in proportion to your physique.
朋友，穿粗条纹的衬衫是有讲究的
There are definite do's and don'ts, good buddy, of wearing a boId stripe shirt.
它必须配深色的
A boId striped shirt caIIs for soIid coIoured or discreetIy patterned suits and ties.
或者图案鲜明的西装和领带
对，给设计师百分之十五小费就行
Yes, aIways tip the styIist 15o/o.
听着，John，我得挂了 T. Boone Pickens来了
Listen John, I've got to go. T. Bone Pickens just waIked in.
开个玩笑 不，不用给沙龙老板小费
Just joking.
No, don't tip the owner of the saIon.
好了吗，John 好的
Okay John, right, got it.
知道了 抱歉了
不，该抱歉的是我 我该先预约的
Sorry.
No, I'm sorry. I shouId've made an appointment.
是很重要的事吗？
Was that anything important?
哦，没什么 谈谈生意
That? Just muIIing over business probIems.
找找机会，飞短流长，闲聊瞎扯而已
Examining opportunities. Exchanging rumours.
你好
Spreading gossip.
-我是Donald Kimball -你好，Pat Bateman
Hi. I'm DonaId KimbaII.
-幸会 -抱歉就这么闯进来了
-Hi. Pat Bateman. Nice to meet you. -Sorry to barge in on you Iike this.
我知道干你们这行的有多忙
I know how busy you guys can get.
那么，呃，我们要谈点什么呢？
So, what's the...
Meredith Powell雇了我
-...topic of discussion? -I've been hired by Meredith PoweII...
调查Paul Allen失踪的事
...to investigate the disappearance of PauI AIIen.
明白了，嗯 Paul失踪的事，嗯
I see, PauI's disappearance, yeah.
这不算正式的问话
It's nothing that officiaI.
-我只是问几个关于Paul Allen和你本人的问题 -要咖啡吗？
I just have some basic questions about PauI and yourseIf.
-不，不必了 -矿泉水？
-Coffee? -No, I'm okay.
不，真的不必
-ApoIIinaris? -No, I'm okay.
能为--
-Kimball，不必麻烦了 -Kimball先生拿瓶矿泉水进来吗？
-Can you bring Mr.... -KimbaII.
小意思
-A bottIe of-- -No, reaIIy, I'm okay.
It's no probIem.
那么我们要谈什么来着？
So, what's the topic of discussion?
Paul Allen失踪的事
Disappearance of PauI AIIen.
呃嗯，对 唔，我还没--
Right. WeII, I....
没听说任何关于他失踪的事呢
I haven't heard anything about the disappearance or anything.
只是没在报纸第六版上看到
Not on page six, at Ieast.
-我想他的家人还不想声张 -懂了 要柠檬汁吗？
-His famiIy wants this kept quiet. -UnderstandabIe.
-不用了，真的 -真的不要，我随时都可以为你拿一杯来的
-Lime? -No, reaIIy. I'm okay.
Sure? I can get you a Iime.
就问几个简单的问题，我存档用的，好吗？
Just some preIiminary questions that I need for my own fiIes, okay?
问吧
Shoot.
-你的年龄？ -27岁
-How oId are you? -27.
-在哪儿上的学？ -哈佛
-Where did you go to schooI? -Harvard. The Harvard Business SchooI.
-然后上了哈佛商学院 -住址？
美国花园大厦，西81街
Your address?
-好极了，很好 -谢谢
American Gardens BuiIding, West 81st Street.
Nice. Very nice.
-你能告诉我什么有关Paul Allen的事？ -我有点摸不着头脑
Thanks.
-What can you teII me about PauI AIIen? -I'm at a Ioss.
-他就是耶鲁那帮人的一分子 -耶鲁那帮人？
-He was part of that whoIe YaIe thing. -YaIe thing?
-对，耶鲁那帮人 -你指的是什么？
Yeah. YaIe thing.
唔，大致就是说那些私底下搞同性恋
What do you mean?
WeII, I think for one that he was probabIy a cIoset homosexuaI...
还大吸可卡因的家伙
...who did a Iot of cocaine. That YaIe thing.
这就是耶鲁那帮人
除了你刚才说的，他还是什么样的人呢？
What kind of a man was he? Besides the information you've just given me?
-这里没什么相互对质的事吧？ -你觉得象吗？
-I hope I'm not being cross-examined here. -Do you feeI Iike that?
不，我没那个意思
No. Not reaIIy.
Paul常去什么地方？
Where did PauI hang out?
-常去的地方？ -你知道的
-Hang out? -Yeah. You know, hang out.
让我想想 嗯，Newport，Harry餐馆
Let me think.
The Newport. Harry's. FIuties.
Fluties，Indochine
Nell餐馆，Cornell俱乐部
Indochine. NeII's. The CorneII CIub.
-纽约游艇俱乐部 -他有游艇吗？
-The New York Yacht CIub. -He had a yacht?
不，他不过常去那儿 -他在哪儿上的学？
-No, he just hung out there. -And where did he go to schooI?
你还不知道吗？
我只是想知道你是否知道
-Don't you know this? -I just wanted to know if you know.
在进耶鲁前，如果我没记错，是在圣保罗学校
Before YaIe? If I remember correctIy, Saint PauI's.
听着，我只是-- 只想帮帮忙
Listen, I just want to heIp.
我明白
I understand.
你们有目击证人或者指纹吗？
Any witnesses or fingerprints?
哦，他的留言机上留话说他去伦敦了
There's a message on his answering machine that says he went to London.
-那么可能他确实去伦敦了，是不是？ -他的女朋友不相信
-Maybe he did. -His girIfriend doesn't think so.
-有人在伦敦见过他吗？ -实际上，有
-Has anyone seen him in London? -ActuaIIy, yes.
但我很难确证
But I've had difficuIty getting an actuaI verification.
一位叫Stephen Hughes的说他在伦敦的餐馆见到过他
A Stephen Hughes said he saw him at a restaurant there.
但我去查了，结果是
But I checked it out and what happened is, he mistook a Herbert Ainsworth for PauI.
他把一位叫Herbert Ainsworth的人 认作Paul了，所以…
-他的公寓遭窃了吗？ -没有
-Had his apartment been burgIarised? -No, actuaIIy it hadn't.
就不见了一些化妆品， 一套西装，和一些行李
ToiIetries were missing. A suit was gone. So was some Iuggage. That's it.
我是说，还没人在做刑事调查，是吧？
Anyone deaIing with the homicide squad?
不，还没有 正如我说过的，我们还不确定
No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure.
基本上还没有看到或听到什么
BasicaIIy, no one's seen or heard anything.
-很典型，不是吗？ -只是很奇怪
-So typicaI, isn't it? -It's just strange.
某一天，某个身边的人
One day someone's waIking around, going to work...
上得好好的班，生龙活虎的， 然而--
什么都没了
-...aIive, and then.... -Nothing.
突然他消失得无影无踪了
PeopIe just disappear.
大地…突然裂开把他吞进去了
The earth just opens up and swaIIows them.
古怪，确实古怪
Eerie. ReaIIy eerie.
听着，我得失陪了
You'II have to excuse me. I have a meeting with CIiff HuxtabIe...
再过20分钟我和Cliff Huxtable 在四季餐厅有个午餐会
四季餐厅？从新市区去不是很远吗？
...at the Four Seasons in 20 minutes.
The Four Seasons? Isn't that a IittIe far uptown?
-我的意思是，你可能要迟到了 -不，这里附近就有一家
Aren't you going to be Iate?
-哦，真的吗？我还不知道呢 -不错，很好的餐厅
No. There's one down here.
-ReaIIy? I didn't know that. -Yes, it's very good.
听着，如果你想起了什么，任何事--
Listen, if anything occurs to you, any information--
-没问题，我会一五一十全告诉你的 -太好了
AbsoIuteIy, I'm 100o/o with you.
耽误你的时间了，Bateman先生
Great. And thanks for your time, Mr. Bateman.
-再会 -再见
-Bye-bye. -Bye.
-我以前没见过你 -你没注意看而已
-I haven't seen you around here. -You just haven't been Iooking.
-想到我的公寓看看吗？ -我一般不去的
WouId you Iike to see my apartment?
I'm not supposed to.
你到底来不来？
Do you want to come to my apartment or not?
我一般不去，但也有例外
I'm not supposed to, but I can make an exception.
你收信用卡吗？
开个玩笑
Do you take a credit card?
来吧，上车
I'm joking. Come on, get in.
我要一个二十几岁的姑娘
I'd Iike a girI, earIy twenties, bIonde, who does coupIes.
金发的，会玩双人的，双人
我没法把金发更为强调，金发女郎
CoupIes. I reaIIy can't stress bIonde enough.
BIonde.
我叫Paul
我叫Paul Allen 你听明白了吗？
I'm PauI. My name is PauI AIIen. You got that?
你叫Chiristie，叫你Christie你才应
You're Christie.
明白了吗？
You are to respond onIy to Christie.
" lf you don't know me by now "
Is that cIear?
" lf you don't know me "
" You will never never know me "
你在喝的是很棒的夏敦埃酒
It's a very fine Chardonnay you're drinking.
我要你把你那儿洗洗干净
" lf you don't know me by now "
I want you to cIean your vagina.
" You will never never know me "
不，从后面来 跪下去
No, from behind.
你的身体很美
Get on your knees.
You have a very nice body.
谢谢，让她上来
Thank you. Send her up.
Christie，出来擦干身体
Christie, get out and dry off, choose a robe.
选件浴袍--不要穿睡衣--
再来客厅见我和我们的客人，喝一杯
Not the Bijan.
Then, come and meet me and our guest in the Iiving room for drinks.
你来了，真可爱
You've arrived! How IoveIy.
把大衣给我吧
Let me take your coat. I'm PauI. How good of you to come.
我叫Paul，你能来真是太好了
头发还不够金黄，不是吗？
Not quite bIonde, are you?
颜色有点暗
More dirty bIonde.
我要叫你Sabrina
I'm going to caII you Sabrina.
我叫Paul Allen
I'm PauI AIIen.
那么
So...
你们不想知道我干哪行的吗？
...don't you want to know what I do?
-不 -不用了
No.
No, not reaIIy.
唔，我在华尔街上班
WeII, I work on WaII Street.
P&P公司
你们听说过吗？
At Pierce & Pierce.
Have you heard of it?
你的家真不错，Paul
You have a reaIIy nice pIace here, PauI.
房租多少？
唔，实际上
How much did you pay for it?
这不干你事，Christie
WeII actuaIIy, that's none of your business.
但我可以明确地告诉你， 房租当然不会便宜
But I can assure you, it certainIy wasn't cheap.
不，别吸烟 这儿禁止吸烟
No. No smoking. Not in here.
在喝Varda truffle？
Varda TruffIe?
我不想让你们喝醉
I don't want you to get drunk, but...
但那儿有很好的夏敦埃酒，你却不喝
...that's a very fine Chardonnay you're not drinking.
喜欢Phil Collins吗？
Do you Iike PhiI CoIIins?
自从1980年Genesis发行了专集Duke之后
I've been a big Genesis fan ever since the reIease of their 1980 aIbum...
我就成了他们的大乐迷
在此之前，我对他们的作品一窍不通
...Duke.
Before that I reaIIy didn't understand any of their work.
它们太艺术了，太费解了
It's too artsy, too inteIIectuaI.
正是在Duke里
It was on Duke, where PhiI CoIIins' presence became more apparent.
Phil Collins脱颖而出
我认为“Invisible Touch”是Genesis 无可争议的最佳单曲
I think InvisibIe Touch is the group's undisputed masterpiece.
它是有关不可捉摸事务的史诗性沉思
It's an epic meditation on intangibiIity.
同时，它又深化丰富了
At the same time, it deepens and enriches...
紧接着三张专集的内涵
...the meaning of the preceding three aIbums.
Christie，把浴袍脱掉
Christie, take off the robe.
请听Banks，Collins和Rutherford的
Listen to the briIIiant ensembIe pIaying of Banks, CoIIins, and Rutherford.
辉煌的合唱
你甚至能听辨出每件乐器的细微差别
You can practicaIIy hear every nuance of every instrument.
Sabrina，把衣服脱掉
Sabrina, remove your dress.
谈到作词和作曲
In terms of IyricaI craftsmanship and sheer song writing...
这张专集攀上了一个新的高峰
...this aIbum hits a new peak of professionaIism.
Sabrina，你为什么不，嗯，跳跳舞呢
Sabrina, why don't you dance a IittIe?
举“Landofi Confusion”的歌词为例
Take the Iyrics to Land of Confusion...
在这首歌里，Phil Collins
...in this song, PhiI CoIIins addresses the probIems of abusive poIiticaI authority.
谈到了政府滥用权力的问题
“In Too Deep”是80年代最感人的流行歌曲
In Too Deep is the most moving pop song of the 1980s...
有关夫妻之间的彼此忠贞
...about monogamy and commitment.
这歌如此积极向上
歌词积极乐观
The song is extremeIy upIifting.
Their Iyrics are as positive and affirmative...
象，呃，任何我所听到的摇滚乐一样
...as anything I've heard in rock.
Christie，跪下来
Christie, get down on your knees, so Sabrina can see your asshoIe.
把屁股对着Sabrina
Phil Collins的独唱生涯
PhiI CoIIins' soIo career...
似乎商业味更浓
...seems to be more commerciaI...
因此狭义地说更让人满意
...and therefore, more satisfying in a narrower way...
特别是象“In the Air Tonight" 和“Against All Odds”这样的歌
...especiaIIy songs Iike In the Air Tonight and Against AII Odds.
Sabrina，别光看呀，用舔的
Sabrina, don't just stare at it. Eat it.
我还认为Phil Collins在乐队的表现
I aIso think that PhiI CoIIins works best within the confines of the group...
比他独唱要好
我强调的是作为一个艺术家
...than as a soIo artist.
And I stress the word ''artist.''
这首是“Sussudio”
This is Sussudio, a great, great song.
一首非常非常好的歌 我个人的最爱
A personaI favourite.
" There's a girl who's been on my mind " 看着镜头
" All the time "
" Su-Sussuido "
" Oh,oh "
" Now,she don't even know my name "
" But l think she likes mejust the same "
" Su-Sussuido "
" Oh,oh "
" Oh,if she'd call me l'd be there "
" l'd come running "
" Anywh ere " Christie，看着镜头
" All of my life "
" l feel so good "
" If l just say the worrd "
" Su-Sussuido "
别碰表
Don't touch the watch.
我们能走了吗？
Can we go now?
还没完呢
We're not through yet.
如果她们性情很好而相貌平平， 还有谁会去理她们
If they have a good personaIity and aren't great Iooking, then who cares?
我们只是打个比方，好吗？
Let's say hypotheticaIIy, okay? What if they have a good personaIity?
如果她们性情好会怎么样？
我知道，我知道
根本没有性情好的女人
I know, I know.
''There are no girIs with good personaIities.''
所谓性情好包括要有一个强壮的身体
A good personaIity consists of a chick with a hardbody...
可以满足各种各样的性需要
...who'II satisfy aII sexuaI demands without being too sIutty...
但不能过分淫荡
并且还要守口如瓶
...and who'II keep her dumb, fucking mouth shut.
拥有良好性情的女人
The onIy girIs with good personaIities, smart...
也许很聪明，也许很有趣， 也许蠢得要死，或者智力超群--
...funny, haIfway inteIIigent, or taIented...
只要上帝才知道这是什么意思-- 都是丑女人
...though God knows what the fuck that means, are ugIy chicks.
毫无疑问，因为这是她们弥补
她们缺乏吸引力的唯一方法
This is because they have to make up for how fucking ugIy they are.
-你们知道Ed Gein怎么谈女人的吗？ -Canal酒吧的领班？
-You know what Ed Gein said? -Ed Gein? Maitre d' at CanaI Bar?
不，50年代的连环杀手，威斯康星州的 -他怎么说的？
-No. SeriaI kiIIer, Wisconsin in the '50s. -And what did Ed say?
“我在街上看到漂亮娘们的时候， 我会想两件事”
''When I see a pretty girI, I think of two things...
“一方面我想和她约会与她聊天，
''...one part of me wants to take her out...
对她照顾备至，小心呵护”
''...taIk to her, be reaI nice and sweet and treat her right.''
那么他另一方面想干吗？
What did the other part of him think?
“把她脑袋插在木棍上会怎么样？”
What her head wouId Iook Iike on a stick.
嗨，我想听听你们的意见
Hi, guys. I want to get your opinion on something.
这是我的名片
It's my business card.
我也决定做张新的了
I decided to get a new one, too.
哦，它--
相对不错，Luis
Very nice, Luis.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着，晚饭去哪儿吃？
What about dinner?
你就会说这个吗，Can Pattern？ “晚饭去他妈的哪儿吃？”
Is that aII you ever have to contribute? What about fucking dinner?
开心点，Bateman，你怎么了？ 早上没做指压按摩吗？
Cheer up there. What's the matter? No shiatsu today?
-再碰我，我就跟你没完 -别激动，伙计
Touch me again and you'II draw back a stump.
失陪了
-HoId on there, IittIe buddy. -Excuse me.
上帝啊，Patrick 干吗在这儿呢？
Patrick, why here?
我看到你对我眉目传情了
我感觉到了
I've seen you Iooking at me.
你火热的身体
I've noticed your...
别害羞
...hot body.
你不知道我等这天等了多久--
Don't be shy.
自从Arizona 206的圣诞派对以来
You can't imagine how Iong I've wanted this, ever since that party at Arizona 206.
你知道的，那天你戴了条 Armani红条纹花呢领带
You know, the one you were wearing that red striped paisIey Armani tie.
我要你 我也要你
I want you.
-Patrick -怎么回事？
I want you, too.
你去哪儿？
-Patrick! -What is it?
我要去还几盘录像带
Where are you going?
I've got to return some video tapes.
Patrick！
I'II caII you.
好的，伦敦--
-伦敦，呃，有定房-- -有和Paul Allen有关的吗？
-没有，定了房，但是-- -Kimball！
I've been wanting to taIk with you! Come in to my office.
我正想跟你谈谈呢，来我的办公室吧
Jean, great jacket. Matsuda?
Jean，你的上衣很漂亮 是Matsuta吗？
能想起Paul失踪那晚你在哪儿吗？
Do you remember where you were the night of PauI's disappearance?
12月20号那天
Which was on December 20?
上帝
God, I guess I was probabIy returning videotapes.
我想我可能去还录像带了
我和一个名叫Veronica的姑娘有个约会
-I had a date with a girI named Veronica. -That's not what I've got.
-和我听说的不一样呀 -什么？
-What? -That's not the information I've received.
我听说的不是这样的
唔，等等
WeII, wait. What information have you received?
-你听说的是怎么样的？ -让我看看
Let me see.
唔--
-你和-- -嗯，我可能记错了
-That you were with-- -WeII, I couId be wrong.
你最后一次见Paul Allen是什么时候？
When was the Iast time you were with PauI AIIen?
我们一同去听一个音乐剧
We'd gone to a new musicaI caIIed...
叫“哦，非洲，勇敢的非洲”
...Oh Africa, Brave Africa. It was a Iaugh riot. That was about it.
是出笑闹剧，就这样
我想我们在Orso餐馆吃了晚饭 不，Peto-- 不，Orso餐馆
I think we had dinner at Orso's. No, PetaIuma. No, Orso's.
我希望能对你有所帮助 日子久了，记忆有点混乱
I hope I've been informative, Iong day. I'm a bit scattered.
我现在也精疲力尽了
I'm a IittIe spent now too.
过一个星期左右吃顿午饭怎么样？
How about Iunch in a week or so, when I've sorted out aII this information?
等我把这些头绪理清之后
好极了 是的，我很愿意
Great, yes, I'd Iike that.
如果我能确定你到底在哪儿
If you couId try and pin down where you were...
在Paul Allen失踪那晚， 我的活就好干多了
...the night of AIIen's disappearance, it wouId make my job a Iot easier.
当然，我会跟你一起努力回忆的
AbsoIuteIy. I'm with you on that one.
Huey Lewis & News
Huey Lewis & the News.
好东西，我在来这儿的路上买的 你听过吗？
Great stuff. I just bought it on my way here. You heard it?
从来没有，我的意思是我不喜欢流行歌手
Never. I mean, I don't reaIIy Iike singers.
-不是个乐迷，是吧？ -我喜欢音乐
Not a big music fan?
No, I Iike music.
因为他们--Huey的歌对我来说太灰调了
Just, they're....
Huey's too bIack sounding for me.
各有所好
WeII, to each his own.
那么，下周一起吃午饭？
So, Iunch next week?
我会去的
I'II be there.
哦！
-复活节前你会给我打电话吗？ -也许吧
WiII you caII me before Easter?
Maybe.
你今晚干什么？
What are you doing tonight?
呃，在River餐馆吃饭
Dinner at the River Cafe. Au Bar afterwards, maybe.
-然后去Au酒吧，也许 -不错
That's nice.
我还不知道你也抽烟呢
I never knew you smoked.
你没留心罢了
You never noticed.
听着，Patrick
Listen, Patrick.
我们能谈谈吗？
Can we taIk?
你看起来…帅极了
You Iook marveIIous.
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to say. You're going to marry Luis.
-你马上要嫁给Lusi了 -这难道不值一提？
Isn't that speciaI?
Patrick
Patrick?
什么事，Courtney？
Yes, Courtney?
如果我在复活节前见不到你
If I don't see you before Easter, have a nice one, okay?
你自己玩得开心点，好吗？
你也是
You, too.
Patrick？
Patrick?
嗯？
Yeah?
没什么
Nothing.
" Pump up the volume "
现在有个说法-- 听我说
Listen to this, there's this theory now...
现在有个说法说 如果你因为和艾滋病人做爱
...that if you can catch AIDS through having sex...
而染上艾滋病， 那么你就有可能得任何一种病
...then you can catch anything!
老年痴呆，肌肉萎缩，血友病
AIzheimer's, muscuIar dystrophy, haemophiIia, Ieukaemia...
白血病，糖尿病，失语症
...diabetes, dysIexia....
我不敢肯定，但我不认为 失语症是病毒引起的
I'm not sure, but I don't think dysIexia is a virus.
可谁知道呢？ 他们才不知道呢
Who knows? They don't know that. Prove it.
证明给我看
-我，上帝 -怎么了？
-Oh God! -What?
It's a fucking miIIigram of sweetener!
这简直就是一小堆甜粉 我是要用它来High的
I want to get high off this, not sprinkIe it on my fucking oatmeaI.
-不是把它洒在我他妈的燕麦粥上 -确实弱得可怜
It's definiteIy weak. But if we do enough of it, we'II be okay.
但我想如果我们多来点，也许会好些
CouId you keep it down, I'm trying to do drugs!
你们能小声点吗？ 我在嗑药呢
-去你的！ -别激动，我们就这么来吧
-Fuck you! -CaIm down!
-We'II do it anyway. -I guess you're right...
这就对了
...if the fag in the next staII thinks it's okay!
如果隔壁的基佬觉得OK了就行了！
-去你的！ -嘿，去你的！
-Fuck you! -Hey, fuck you!
对不起，哥儿们，激素的作用
Sorry, dude. Steroids.
好了，我们来吧
Okay, Iet's do it.
" I wanna know "
" What you're thinking "
" There are some things you can't hide "
" I wanna know "
" What you're feeIing "
" Tell me what's on your mind "
Craig去哪儿了？
Where did Craig go?
嗯，戈尔巴乔夫在楼下 McDermoctt去跟他签
WeII, Gorbachev is downstairs. McDermott went to sign a peace treaty...
美俄和平协议去了
...between the United States and Russia. He's the one behind GIasnost, you know.
他是公开化政策的幕后策划人
He said he was in mergers and acquisitions.
-他说他做的是股权的并购和重组 -你们搞错了，是吧？
You're not confused, are you?
没有，怎么会
No, not reaIIy.
-戈尔巴乔夫不在楼下 -Karen说得对
Gorbachev is not downstairs.
Caron's right. Gorbachev's not downstairs. He's at TunneI.
戈尔巴乔夫是不在楼下 他在隧道里
问我个问题吧
Ask me a question.
好吧，你是干什么的？
So, what do you do?
我是，呃，基本上在 和杀人犯和死刑打交道
I'm into murders and executions mostIy.
-你喜欢这活吗？ -唔，这要看情况 干吗这么问？
Do you Iike it?
WeII, it depends. Why?
唔，我认识的那些做股票的家伙 都不喜欢玩股票
WeII, most guys I know, who work in mergers and acquisitions...
...reaIIy don't Iike it.
好吧，你怎么猜到的？
So...
...where do you work out?
你不会认为我真的很笨吧？
-You think I'm dumb, don't you? -What?
-什么？ -你认为我很笨，你认为所有的模特都是笨蛋
You think I'm dumb. You think aII modeIs are dumb.
不，我才不呢
No. I reaIIy don't.
那没什么，我不在乎
That's okay. I don't mind.
你挺讨人喜欢的
There's something sweet about you.
在玩填字游戏？
Doing the crossword?
要我帮忙吗？
You need any heIp?
-Jean？ -什么事，Patrick？
Jean?
Yes, Patrick?
你能陪我吃顿晚饭吗？
WouId you Iike to accompany me to dinner?
我是说，如果你没事的话
That is, if you're not doing anything.
嗯，不，我没事 我没任何安排
No. I don't have any pIans.
好
WeII...
真是太巧了
...isn't this a coincidence?
-听着，我们要去哪儿？ -随你便
-Where shouId we go? -Anywhere you want.
我们别管我想去哪儿 你到底想去哪儿？
Let's not think about what I want. How about anywhere you want?
我不知道，Patrick 我没法做这样的决定
I don't know. I can't make this decision.
快点，你想去哪儿？
Come on.
Where do you want to go?
不管想去哪儿，告诉我 我会设法安排的
Anywhere you want to. Just say it. I can get us in anywhere.
那…
What about...
去Dorsia怎么样？
...Dorsia?
好
So...
Dorsia是Jean想去的地方
...Dorsia is where Jean wants to go.
唔，我不知道该去哪儿 你想去哪儿我就去哪儿
I don't know. No, we'II go wherever you want to go.
Dorsia很好
Dorsia is fine.
是Dorsia吗？
Dorsia, yes?
-是的，能为我在，呃，今晚9点留两个座吗？ -我们的座定完了
Yeah, can you take two tonight at, Iet's say, 9:00?
We're totaIIy booked.
真的吗？太好了
ReaIIy? That's great.
-我是说全定完了 -9点两个座？好极了
No, I said we are totaIIy booked.
Two at 9:00? Perfect.
再会
See you then.
什么事？
Yeah? You're...
你今天...穿得很得体
...dressed okay.
-你没留姓名 -他们认识我
You didn't give a name.
They know me.
能在7点到我家来会面吗？
Why don't you meet me at my pIace at 7:00 for drinks?
喝两杯
还有，Jean
And Jean?
我们出去前你最好换身衣服
You'II want to change before we go out.
Patrick，这儿真美
Patrick, it's so eIegant.
多好的风景啊
What a wonderfuI view.
Jean
Jean?
果汁冰淇淋？
Sorbet?
谢谢，Patrick 我想来点
Thanks, Patrick. I'd Iove some.
-你不也来点吗？ -我在节食，不过谢谢你了
Do you want a bite?
I'm on a diet. But thank you.
你没必要减肥 在开玩笑，是吗？
You don't need to Iose any weight. You're kidding, right?
你体型好极了 很健康
You Iook great. Very fit.
人总是想再瘦点，看起来更漂亮点
You can aIways be thinner.
Look better.
哦，也许我们不该出去吃饭 我不想动摇你的意志
Maybe we shouIdn't go out to dinner. I don't want to ruin your wiIIpower.
没事，这没什么
No, it's aII right.
我本来就控制不住
I'm not very good at controIIing it anyway.
听好
So Iisten...
你一生真正想干的是什么？
...what do you reaIIy want to do with your Iife?
简单说说，概括一下
Just briefIy summarise.
还有别跟我说你喜欢 看孩子之类的，好吗？
Don't teII me you enjoy working with chiIdren, okay?
唔，我想旅游还有也许会学校念书
WeII, I'd Iike to traveI and maybe go back to schooI, but...
但我不能确定
...I don't reaIIy know.
我正处在最多选择的人生阶段
I'm at a point in my Iife where there seem to be so many possibiIities.
可我--我不知道-- 我一点也不能确定
I don't know. I'm just so unsure.
你有男朋友吗？
Do you have a boyfriend?
-不，没有 -有意思
No, not reaIIy.
Interesting.
你有合适的对象吗？ 我是说真的
Are you seeing anyone? I mean, seriousIy?
也许有
Maybe. I don't know.
我也不知道，真的不知道
Not reaIIy.
Jean
Jean?
你有成就感吗？
Do you feeI fuIfiIIed?
我是说，你这一生？
I mean, in your Iife?
我想有点吧 我专心工作已经很长时间了
I guess I do.
For a Iong time, I was too focused on my work.
但现在我已经开始 考虑改变自我了，你知道的
But now, I've reaIIy begun to think about changing myseIf.
发展一下自我
DeveIoping and growing.
发展，很高兴听你这么说
Growing. I'm gIad you said that.
你知道吗，呃，TedBundy的第一只狗
Did you know that Ted Bundy's first dog, a coIIie, was named Lassie?
一只牧羊犬，叫Lassie？
-你听说过吗？ -谁是Ted Bundy？
Had you heard that?
Who's Ted Bundy?
别管他了
Forget it.
那是什么？
-What's that? -Duct tape.
胶带，我用它来，呃，粘东西
I need it for taping something.
Patrick
Patrick?
你有没有想过…让一个人快乐？
Have you ever wanted to make someone happy?
什么？别！ 把它放在垫子上
What? No! Put it in the carton.
对不起
Sorry.
Jean？
Jean?
-你说什么？ -呃，让一个人开心？
What?
Make someone happy.
你有没有想过？
Have you ever wanted to?
我在找寻，呃
I'm Iooking for....
我想应该说我只想和某些特殊的人
You couId say, I just want a meaningfuI reIationship with someone speciaI.
保持良好的关系
Patrick？Patrick？ 我知道你在那儿
Patrick! I know you're there.
快接电话，你这个坏小子
Pick up the phone, you bad boy. What are you up to tonight?
你今晚要干什么？ 是我，别想躲开我
It's me. Don't try to hide.
希望你不是在和什么路边找来的女儿鬼混 因为你是我的Bateman先生
I hope you're not with some woman you picked up, because you're mine.
我的邻家男孩
My boy next door.
不管怎么说你一个电话也没给我打 尽管你答应过的
Anyway, you never caIIed me back. I'II Ieave a message for Jean, too...
我还要给Jean也留个言，让她提醒你
...to remind you that we're having dinner with MeIania and TayIor.
可我们得和Malania和Taylor吃饭
你知道Melania的 她去Sweet Briar了
You know MeIania, she went to Sweet Briar.
我们会在Cornell俱乐部会面
We're meeting at the CorneII CIub. So, I'II caII you tomorrow morning, honey.
我明天早上会给你来电话的，亲爱的
Sorry, I know you hate that.
哦，抱歉，我知道 你不喜欢这么叫你
再见，Patrick 再见，大时代总裁先生，再见
Bye, Patrick. Bye, Mr. Big Time CEO. Bye-bye.
是Evelyn吗？
Was that EveIyn?
你还和她约会？
Are you stiII seeing her?
对不起，我没权这么问
I'm sorry. I have no right to ask that.
你要我离开吗？
Do you want me to go?
是的
Yeah.
我想我会控制不住自己的
I don't think I can controI myseIf.
我明白，我该离开的 我知道我总会和得不到的男人纠缠不清
I know I shouId go.
I know I have a tendency to get invoIved with unavaiIabIe men.
我是说
I mean....
你真要我走吗？
Do you want me to go?
我想如果你留下来
I think if you stay, something bad wiII happen.
就会发生一些不好的事
我想我会伤害你的
I think I might hurt you.
你不想受到伤害，是吗？
You don't want to get hurt, do you?
不，当然不
No, I guess not.
我不想被打得鼻青脸肿的
I don't want to get bruised.
说的没错，你是该走了
You're right. I shouId go.
哦，别忘了你明天中午要和Donald Kimbll 在Smith & Wolenski餐厅吃饭
Don't forget you have a Iunch date tomorrow with DonaId KimbaII...
...at Smith and WoIIensky's.
谢谢
Thanks.
这事我都忘光了
It sIipped my mind compIeteIy.
他失踪的那晚--
So...
...the night he disappeared, any new thoughts about what you did?
你想起你干了什么了吗？
还是不能确定 唔，我冲了个澡
I'm not sure. I had a shower...
吃了果汁冰淇淋？
-...and some sorbet? -I think you're getting your dates mixed up.
我想你把约会的人搞错了
But how?
怎么会呢？
Where do you pIace PauI that night?
你说那天晚上…Paul在哪儿？
根据他的记事本， 经他的秘书确证
According to his date book and this was verified by his secretary...
他和Marcus Halberstram一起吃的晚饭
...he had dinner with Marcus HaIberstram.
-还有呢？ -我询问了他
-And? -I've questioned him.
-Marcus吗？ -是的，他否认了这点，尽管一开始他也不能确定
Yes. And he denies it. Though at first he couIdn't be sure.
-但他否认了 -是的
-But he denied it? -Yes.
那么Marcus有不在肠证人吗？
-WeII, does Marcus have an aIibi? -Yes.
-有 -他有吗？你确定？
-He does? You're sure? -I checked it out. It's cIean.
我查过了，没问题
那么，你当时在哪儿？
Now where were you?
Marcus在哪儿？
Where was Marcus?
他没和Paul Allen在一起
-He wasn't with PauI AIIen. -Who was he with?
-那他和谁在一起？ -他在…
He was at AtIantis...
Atlantis和…
...with Craig McDermott...
Craig McDermott，Freerick Dibble， Hary Newman，George Butner…
...Frederick DibbIe, Harry Newman, George Butner and...
还有…你在一起
...you.
哦，对啦，是的 当然如此
Right. Of course.
我们在等Paul Allen来
We had wanted PauI AIIen to come.
但他另有安排
But he had made pIans.
我想我和Victoria吃饭是在第二天晚上
I guess I had dinner with Victoria the foIIowing night.
我个儿以为，这家伙可能惹了点麻烦
PersonaIIy, I think the guy went a IittIe nutso.
因此出去避避风头 也许他真去伦敦了，去闲逛喝酒什么的
SpIit town for a whiIe. Maybe he did go to London.
Sightseeing, drinking, whatever.
不管怎么说，我相信他迟早会现身的 我的意思是，认为
Anyway, I'm pretty sure he'II turn up sooner or Iater.
To think that one of his friends kiIIed him for no reason wouId be too ridicuIous.
他被他的某个朋友莫名其妙地杀了 无论如何有点可笑
是这样吗，Patrick？
Isn't that right, Patrick?
Christie，Christie
Christie. Christie.
我不知道我该不该去 上次出来我就进急诊室了
I'm not so sure about this. I had to go to Emergency after Iast time.
这次绝对不会象上次那样了，我保证
This won't be anything Iike Iast time. I promise.
我不相信
I don't think so.
快上车吧，我们就谈一分钟
Just come in the Iimo and taIk to me for a minute.
司机在这儿呢，你很安全的
The driver's here. You'II be safe.
绝对不会象上次那样 我保证
-Nothing Iike Iast time, promise. -AII right.
好吧
So, you're Iooking great, how have you been?
嗯，你看起来很美 最近怎么样？
-实际上我上次差点都要动手术了 -真的吗？
I actuaIIy might need a IittIe surgery after Iast time.
我朋友甚至跟我说我应该请个律师
My friend toId me I shouId maybe even get a Iawyer.
律师太麻烦了
Lawyers are so compIicated. Don't do that.
别听她的
这儿有张支票
Here's a check.
呃，现在一半，完事另一半
HaIf now, haIf Iater.
好吧，你就叫Christie
Okay. Your name is Christie.
我们要和我的一个朋友，Elizabeth会面
We're meeting a friend of mine, EIizabeth.
她马上就会到我的新公寓来的
She'II be joining us in my new apartment shortIy.
你会喜欢她的，她是个很好的姑娘
You'II Iike her. She's a very nice girI.
你看起来真面熟 到过Dalton吗？
You Iook very famiIiar. Did you go to DaIton?
我想我在Surf酒吧遇到过你，对不对？ 和Spicey在一起？
I think I met you at the Surf Bar, didn't I? With Spicey?
唔，也许不是和Spicey，但肯定在Surf酒吧 你知道的，Surf酒吧
Maybe not, but definiteIy at Surf Bar.
You know the Surf Bar? Anyway, Surf Bar sucks now, it's terribIe.
不管怎么说，Surf酒吧现在糟透了，真糟
I went to a birthday party there for MaIcoIm Forbes. Oh my God, pIease.
到那儿去参加Malcolm Forbes的生日派对 哦，上帝啊，饶了我吧
这比你另外那个公寓还要好
This is nicer than your other apartment.
哦，没那么夸张
It's not that nice.
-你们两个怎么认识的？ -哦，上帝，我们在…
Where did you two meet?
Oh God! We met at the Kentucky Derby in 1985.
哦，上帝，肯德基的Derby认识的 85或者86年
Or 1986. You were hanging out with that bimbo AIIison PooIe.
你那时候和那个淫荡的Allison Poole 混在一起，真是个风骚货
-Hot number. -What do you mean, she was a hot number.
你什么意思？ 她不是风骚货
只要你有白金卡，她就给你做口交 这娘们在日光沙龙干，你知道的
A pIatinum card got you a bIow job.
She worked in a tanning saIon, need I say more?
你干哪行的？
What do you do?
她是…我侄女
She's my cousin.
-呃 -她从…巴黎来
She's from France.
你的电话呢？我得给Harley打个电话
Where's your phone? I've got to caII HarIey.
你在哪儿度暑假，南Hampton？
Where do you summer? Southampton?
-不 -哦，上帝，是他的留言机
No.
Oh God, it's his machine.
-现在是凌晨3点 -他是卖药的，现在生意正好呢
It's 3:00 in the morning.
He's a goddamn drug deaIer! These are his peak hours.
-别告诉你在这儿 -我怎么会呢？
-Don't teII him you're here. -Why wouId I?
这味道真怪
This tastes weird.
Harley，是我，我需要你的服务 随你怎么理解这意思
HarIey, it's me. I need your services. TransIate that however you want.
-我在-- -Paul Allen家
I'm at....
-Who? -PauI AIIen.
-谁？ -Paul Allen家
PauI AIIen's.
我要那玩意儿，笨蛋 不管怎么说，我在Paul Norman家，一会儿再给你打
I want the number, idiot. Anyway, I'm at PauI Norman's. I'II try again Iater.
要是明晚在Canal酒吧看不到你 我就会让我的理发师找你算帐
See you tomorrow night, or I'm gonna sick my hairdresser on you.
你认识那个失踪的家伙吗？
Did you know that guy who disappeared?
他不也在P&P工作吗？ 他是你朋友吗？
Didn't he work at Pierce & Pierce? Was he your friend?
不是
No.
你有可乐吗？或者Halcyon？
Do you have any coke or HaIcyon? I wouId take a HaIcyon.
-我想来杯Halcyon -听着
我只想看看
I wouId just Iike to see the two of you get it on.
你们两个…干起来
有什么不妥吗？
What's wrong with that? It's totaIIy disease-free.
肯定不会染上病的
-Patrick，你疯了 -来吧
Patrick, you're a Iunatic.
Come on. Don't you find Christie attractive?
你不认为Christie很吸引人吗？
别来色的，我没心情讲荤段子
Let's not get Iewd. I'm in no mood for a Iewd conversation.
来吧
-我觉得这很让人兴奋 -他老这么干吗？
I think it wouId be a turn on.
Does he do this aII the time?
Christie，你没喝你的酒
Christie, you're not drinking your wine.
你是说你从来没和女的搞过？
Are you teIIing me you've never done it with a girI?
没有，我不是同性恋
No! I'm not a Iesbian.
你为什么认为我会干这个？
Why wouId you think I'd be into that?
唔，你去找Sararh Lawrence就为了一件事
-You went to Sarah Lawrence, for one. -Those are Sarah Lawrence guys, Patrick.
那些是Sarah Lawrence那帮家伙干的 你让我感觉怪怪的
You're making me feeI weird.
你知道
Did you know...
Whitney Houston的首张密纹唱片
...that Whitney Houston's debut LP...
叫做“Simply Whitney Houston"
...caIIed simpIy, Whitney Houston...
包含了四首第一流的单曲？
...had four number one singIes on it?
你知道吗，Christie？
Did you know that, Christie?
你到底听不听Whiteny Houston的歌？
You actuaIIy Iisten to Whitney Houston?
你有她的CD吗？
You own a Whitney Houston CD?
不止一张？
More than one?
这么多精彩的曲目里挑最好的相当困难
It's hard to choose a favourite among so many great tracks...
但这首“Greatest Love of All” 是有史以来
...but The Greatest Love of AII is one of the most powerfuI songs ever written...
最好最劲的歌曲之一
关于自我尊严的维护
...about seIf-preservation and dignity.
这事跨越国界的全球之声
Its universaI message crosses aII boundaries and instiIs one...
并且潜移默化地 把这样一个希望告诉人们
现在开始改善自我
...with the hope that it's not too Iate to better ourseIves.
还不算太晚
因为，Elizabeth
Since...
在我们生活的这个世界 和别人同情连心是不可能的
...it's impossibIe in this worId we Iive in...
...to empathise with others, we can aIways empathise with ourseIves.
但我们总能和自己同情连心吧
这是很重要的一点 确实至关重要
It's an important message, cruciaI, reaIIy.
而它通过这张专集优美地传达出来
It's beautifuIIy stated on the aIbum.
竟敢打我的脸！
Not the face, you bitch! Not the fucking face!
臭婊子，竟敢打我的脸 你这个臭婊子！
You, piece of bitch trash!
我想要一个确定的承诺
I want a firm commitment.
我想，呃，Evelyn 我们已经没什么共同语言了
I think, EveIyn, that we've Iost touch.
为什么？怎么了？
Why? What's wrong?
我疯狂嗜杀的渴求
My need to engage in homicidaI behaviour on a massive scaIe, cannot be corrected.
无法遏制
但除此之外再没什么可以满足我的渴求
But I have no other way to fuIfiI my needs.
-我们得好好谈谈 -谈什么，Patrick？
We need to taIk.
-TaIk about what? -It's over, EveIyn. It's aII over.
我们完了，Evelyn
一切都完了
别激动，别激动 我很抱歉又提起结婚的事
Touchy, touchy. I'm sorry I brought up the wedding.
我们不谈这个了，好吗？ 好，来杯咖啡吗？
Let's just avoid the issue, aII right?
Now, are we having coffee?
我是认真的，我们已经完了 不是开玩笑
I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over, us. This is no joke.
呃，我想我们以后都别再见面了
I don't think we shouId see each other any more.
可是你的朋友也是我的朋友 我的朋友也是你的朋友
But your friends are my friends, and my friends are your friends.
我想这是不可能的 你是不是有点--
I don't think it wouId work.
我知道你的朋友也是我的朋友， 并且，呃，我都想过了
-You have a IittIe something-- -I know that your friends are my friends.
I've thought about that. You can have them.
你还可以继续和他们交往
-你是当真的，是吗？ -是的
-You're reaIIy serious, aren't you? -Yes, I am.
-那我们过去的一切呢？ -我们根本没有什么过去
But what about the past?
-Our past? -We never reaIIy shared one.
-你真冷血 -不
-You're inhuman. -No. I'm in touch with humanity.
我很有人情味
Evelyn，我，呃，很抱歉 我只是，呃--
EveIyn, I'm sorry. I just....
你对我而言并不很重要
You're not terribIy important to me.
哦，不！
Oh, no!
不，不，Patrick
我知道我有时候… 行事古怪
I know my behaviour can be erratic sometimes.
你想让我怎么样？ 你到底想怎么样？
What do you want me to do? What is it that you want?
如果你真想为我做点什么 现在就别这样惹人注目
If you reaIIy want to do something for me then stop making this scene, right now.
哦，上帝，我真不敢相信
Oh God, I can't beIieve this.
我要走了 我把事情都说清楚了，我该走了
I'm Ieaving now. I've assessed the situation and I'm going.
-你要去哪儿？ -我要走了
-Where are you going? -I'm just Ieaving.
可去哪儿？
But where?
我得去还几盘录像带
I have to return some video tapes.
来，小猫咪
Here kitty, kitty.
哦，上帝，你在干吗？
Oh my god! What are you doing?
住手
Stop that!
放下武器！马上放下！
Drop the weapon! Drop it now! Get on the ground!
趴下来！把你的--
熬夜加班吗，Smith先生？
Burning the midnight oiI, Mr. Smith?
嘿，别忘了签字
Hey, don't forget to sign in.
Howard，我是Bateman Patrick Bateman
HaroId, it's Bateman. Patrick Bateman.
你是我的律师， 因为我想你该知道我杀了很多人
You're my Iawyer. I think you shouId know I've kiIIed a Iot of peopIe.
在新城区的一间公寓里 杀了几个三陪女郎
Some escort girIs in an apartment uptown.
呃，几个流浪汉，也许五或十个
Some homeIess peopIe, maybe five or ten. An NYU girI I met in CentraI Park.
中央公园碰到的一个纽约女大学生
我把她扔在某家炸饼店 后面的停车场了
I Ieft her in a parking Iot behind a donut shop.
我用钉枪杀了Bethany， 我以前的女朋友
I kiIIed Bethany, my oId girIfriend, with a naiI gun.
还有，还有，还有别的几个人 一些牵着狗的老芦柴棒
And some man, some oId faggot with a dog.
上星期，我，呃--
Last week, I kiIIed another girI with a chainsaw.
我用一把电锯杀了另一个姑娘
我是迫不得已的，她差点就溜了
I had to, she aImost got away.
还有--
There was someone eIse there, I can't remember, maybe a modeI.
其他一些 我记不起来了， 也许是模特--她也死了
还有，呃，Paul Allen
She's dead, too.
And PauI AIIen. I kiIIed PauI AIIen with an axe in the face.
我用一把斧头劈开了他的脸
他的尸体在地狱厨房的浴缸里腐烂着呢
His body is dissoIving in a bathtub in HeII's Kitchen.
我不想在这里留下任何东西 我想我大概杀了…二十个人
I don't want to Ieave anything out here. I guess I've kiIIed maybe 20 peopIe.
也许四十！
Maybe 40.
我把很多都录下来了
I have tapes of a Iot of it.
有些姑娘还看过这些带子
Some of the girIs have seen the tapes.
我甚至，呃
I even....
吃了一些他们的脑子
I ate some of their brains...
我想试试做点菜
...and I tried to cook a IittIe.
今晚，我，呃--
Tonight I...
我被迫杀了很多很多人！
...just had to kiII a Iot of peopIe!
并且，嗯
我想我逃不掉了…这回
I'm not sure...
...I'm going to get away with it this time.
因此，呃--我是说
I mean....
我想…
I guess, I'm a pretty....
我是个相当，呃--
我是说，我想 我是个很变态的家伙
I'm a pretty sick guy.
好
So...
如果你明天回来了
...if you get back tomorrow...
我也许会去Harry酒吧
...I may show up at Harry's Bar.
你知道的
So, you know...
保持清醒
...keep your eyes open.
好了
哦！
你是在赴我2点钟约会的吗？
Are you my 2:00?
-不 -我能为你效劳吗？
No.
Can I heIp you?
我在找…Paul Allen的家
I'm Iooking for...
...PauI AIIen's pIace.
-他…不是住这儿吗？ -不，他不住这儿
Doesn't he Iive here?
No. He doesn't.
你肯定吗？
Are you sure?
你是在Time上看到了广告？
You saw the ad in the Times?
不，是的 我是说，是的
No.
Yeah. I mean yeah.
-在Time上 -我根本没在Time上登过广告
-In the Times. -There was no ad in the Times.
我想你该离开这儿了
I think you shouId go now.
可我想--
But I think....
我想知道这里发生了什么事？
-I want to know what happened here. -Don't make any troubIe, pIease.
请你别惹麻烦
我建议你马上走
I suggest you go.
别回来
Don't come back.
我不会的
I won't. Don't worry.
别担心
Patrick Bateman办公室
-Patrick Bateman's office. -Jean, I need heIp!
-Jean？我需要你的帮助 -Patrick，是你吗？
Patrick? Is that you?
Jean，我不--
I'm not....
Craig McDermott来电说想和你， David Van Patten和Tim Bryce在Harry酒吧会面
McDermott caIIed. He wants to meet you, Van Patten and Bryce at Harry's for drinks.
哦，上帝，你在说什么呀，蠢娘们？
What did you say, you dumb bitch?
-Patrick，我听不清你在说什么 -我在干什么呀？
-Patrick, I can't hear you. -What am I doing?
你在哪儿，Patrick？出什么事了？
Where are you? What's wrong?
我想我不能，Jean，去，呃
I don't think I'm gonna make it...
办公室了，今天下午
...to the office this afternoon.
为什么？
Why?
-我说了不行 -怎么了，Patrick？你没事吧？
Just say no!
What is it? Are you aII right?
别装出那么难过的样子了
Stop sounding so fucking sad!
天哪！
Jesus!
-这是三个人的座位 -Bateman，你看来很不高兴，今天过得不好吗？
TabIe for three.
Bateman, you're Iooking a IittIe wiId-eyed. Rough day at the office?
嘿，看，Bryce回来了 他在喝矿泉水
Bryce is back. And he's drinking mineraI water.
他大变样了，可是他还是定不到位子
He's changed man, except he stiII can't get a reservation to save his Iife.
为什么不去150 Wooster碰碰运气呢？
Why don't you try 150 Wooster?
没定好位子我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere unIess we have a reservation.
Le Cirque，Flamingo East，Oyster酒吧 来吧，伙计们，我们去定个座吧
Le Cirque, FIamingo East, Oyster Bar. Come on, faggots, Iet's get a res.
别脱衬衫，好像吊带松了
Keep your shirt on. Maybe Iose the suspenders.
定8点半的座
-I need a reservation for 8:30. -Excuse me, gentIeman. Right back.
失陪一会儿，马上回来
10点不行，不行
10:00 wouId not be any good. No.
快给他们打电话，把电话给我，我来打 我会给你回电的
Just fucking caII them. Give me the phone, I'II do it.
面对现实吧，日本人在九十年代末 就会垄断这个国家的大部分财富了
Face it, the Japanese wiII own most of this country by the end of the 90s.
闭嘴，Carnes，他们别想
Shut up, Carnes, they wiII not.
嗯，Harold，你听到我的留言了吗？
So, HaroId, did you get my message?
天哪，听到了，真够搞笑的 其实是你留的，对吧？
Jesus, yes. That was hiIarious. That was you, wasn't it?
-是啊，自然是 -Bateman杀了Allen还有三陪女
-Yes, naturaIIy. -Bateman kiIIing AIIen and escort girIs?
-真有趣，够好玩 -你到底什么意思？
-That's fabuIous. That's rich. -What exactIy do you mean?
你的留言啊 顺便问一下，Davis，Cynthia好吗？ 你还和她约会，是吗？
The message you Ieft.
So, Davis, how is Cynthia? You two stiII together?
等-等，Harold，你什么意思啊？
Wait, HaroId, what do you mean?
抱歉，没什么 很高兴见到你
Excuse me. Nothing. It's good to see you.
那是Edward Towers吗？
Is that Edward Towers?
Carnes，等等，呃--
Carnes, wait.
Davis，我不会到处乱讲的 你的玩笑开得够水平
Davis.
I'm not one to bad mouth anyone, your joke was amusing.
但是，朋友，你犯了个致命的错误
But come on, man, you had one fataI fIaw:
Bateman胆小如鼠
Bateman is such a dork...
无聊，没骨气，还没肌肉
...such a boring, spineIess Iightweight.
如果你说是Bryce或者McDermott干的话… 不管怎么说，很搞笑
Now, if you'd said Bryce or McDermott....
请恕我失陪，我真的得走了
Otherwise, it was amusing. Excuse me...
-...I reaIIy must be going. -Wait.
等等，呃--站住
Stop.
我真的干了，Carnes
I did it, Carnes.
我杀了他
I kiIIed him.
我是Patrick Bateman
I'm Patrick Bateman.
我把Allen的头砍下来了
I chopped AIIen's fucking head off.
我在留言里说的都是实话
The whoIe message I Ieft on your machine was true.
抱歉，我真的得走了
Excuse me. I reaIIy must be going.
不，不，听着
No! Listen, don't you know who I am?
你还不知道我是谁吗？
我不是Davis，我就是Patrick Bateman
I'm not Davis, I'm Patrick Bateman!
我们常在电话上聊天的
We taIk on the phone aII the time!
你认不出我来了吗？
Don't you recognise me?
你是我的律师
You're my Iawyer.
现在，Carnes，听我说
Now Carnes, Iisten.
给我仔细听着
Listen very, very carefuIIy.
我杀了Paul Allen
I kiIIed PauI AIIen...
我喜欢这么干
...and I Iiked it.
我说得再清楚不过了
I can't make myseIf any cIearer.
可这根本不可能 而且我也不觉得这有趣了
But that's simpIy not possibIe. And I don't find this funny anymore.
这绝不是编出来的 为什么不可能？
It never was supposed to be! Why isn't it possibIe?
-就是不可能 -为什么，你这个蠢货？
-It's just not. -Why not, you stupid bastard?
因为我和Pual Allen刚吃过两次饭
Because I had dinner with PauI AIIen twice in London...
10天前在伦敦
-...just ten days ago. -No, you...
不，你…
-不可能的 -现在恕我失陪了
-...didn't. -Now, if you'II excuse me.
我们已经看到了相互猜忌的恶果
各州政府间相互欺骗，相互交易
当我们意识到外交政策 不能光由一个委员会制定
We need to find a way to co-operate...
...whiIe reaIising foreign poIicies can't be run by committee.
我们必须找到一条相互合作的道路
而且我相信越来越多的人开始认识到
I beIieve there's now the growing sense...
相互合作会让我们事半功倍
...that we can accompIish more by co-operating.
而最终，这将是对已反伊朗事件面目出现的
And in the end, this may be the eventuaI bIessing in disguise...
混乱局面顺利解决的最好祝福
...to come out of the Iran-Contra mess.
他怎么能这样瞪着眼睛撒谎？
How can he Iie Iike that?
-他怎么能放这种屁？ -放什么屁？
-How can he puII that shit? -What shit?
好了，你们在哪儿定了座？
Now where do we have reservations at?
我不饿，可我想在什么地方定个位子
I'm not hungry, but I'd stiII Iike a reservation.
你怎么能这么--
How can he be so fucking...
我不知道该怎么说，对此这么冷血？
...I don't know, cooI about it?
有些人生来冷血，我想
Some guys are just born cooI, I guess.
Bateman？
Bateman? What are you so fucking zany about?
-你在乐什么呀？ -我是个快乐的露营者
I'm just a happy camper.
快乐的不得了！
Rockin' and a-roIIin'!
哦，弟兄们，看呀
他做出一副无辜的老头的样子， 可是骨子里--
He presents himseIf as a harmIess oId codger.
可是骨子里--
But inside...
...but inside....
可是骨子里毫无所谓
But inside doesn't matter.
骨子里怎么样？相信吗， Bryce，我们真在听你说呢
Inside? Yes, inside? BeIieve it or not, Bryce, we're actuaIIy Iistening to you.
来吧，Bateman，你怎么认为？
Come on, Bateman, what do you think?
-无所谓 -谁出的馊主意要的干啤？
Whatever.
Whose moronic idea was it to order dry beers?
我要苏格兰威士忌
I need a scotch.
再没有什么障碍需要逾越
There are no more barriers to cross.
所有桀傲不驯者，精神错乱者 作奸犯科者所共有的不安
AII I have in common with the uncontroIIabIe and the insane...
所有我犯过的罪行造成的伤害
...the vicious and the eviI, aII the mayhem I have caused...
以及我对这一切的漠视
...and my utter indifference toward it, I have now surpassed.
我现在都成功逾越了
我的痛苦恒久而深切
My pain is constant and sharp.
我不希望世界为任何人变得更好
And I do not hope for a better worId for anyone.
实际上，我要把我的痛苦加诸别人的身上
In fact, I want my pain to be infIicted on others.
我不希望谁能幸免
I want no one to escape.
可即使我坦言相陈
But even after admitting this, there is no catharsis.
我依然没有得以疏解
我无法逃脱我的罪罚
My punishment continues to eIude me.
我也不能再更深地认识自我
And I gain no deeper knowIedge of myseIf.
我所说的再无新意可挖
No new knowIedge can be extracted from my teIIing.
这番自白因此…毫无意义
This confession has meant nothing.
" Abracadoo "
" I Iose you "
" We can't avoid the cIash "
" The big mistake "
" Now we're gonna pay and pay "
" I guess you know I never wanted anyone "
" More than you "
" Lived aII our best times "
" But I know you'II hoId your head up high "
" There's nothing we have to say "
" There is nothing in our eyes "
" But there's something in the air "
" Something I have to say "
" There's something in the air "
" Who feeIs it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Shows it "
" Who feeIs it "
" Knows it "
" Who Ioves it "
" Shows it "
" Who feeIs it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Shows it "
"Come on So what you gonna do with a broken heart "
" What you gonna do when they put you down "
" Move to the hip groove underground "
" What you gonna do when you miss your mark "
" ChiII out Choose a brand-new start "
" How does it feeI to be back on top "
" It's good,uh-huh And you don't stop "
" Who feeIs it "
" Knows it "
" Who Ioves it "
" Shows it "
" Who feeIs it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Yeah,I've been watching me faII "
" For it seems Iike years "
" Watching me grow smaII "
" I watch me "
" Disappear "
" SIipping out my ordinary worId "
" Out of my or diaries "
" I'm watching me "
" Scream "
" FaII "